[{"stepName": "Identify Motion of objects", "stepNumber": 1, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many moving objects are present?", "options": [1, 3, 6, 5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083"], "showfc": []}, {"question": "How many strings are there?", "options": [0, 4, 2, 3], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "showfc": []}, {"question": "How many contacting surfaces are there?", "options": [1, 3, 0, 2], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "showfc": []}]}, {"stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block", "stepNumber": 2, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on red block?", "options": ["T\u2081 downwards", "T\u2081 upwards"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "showfc": ["Upward Forces T\u2081,", "Downward Forces "]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the y-direction", "options": ["+30+T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "-30+T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "-30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for yellow block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081"], "answer": 2}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "options": ["T\u2081 downwards", "T\u2081 upwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081"], "showfc": ["Upward Forces ", "Downward Forces T\u2081,"]}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "options": ["T\u2082 upwards", "T\u2082 downwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081"], "showfc": ["Upward Forces T\u2082,", "Downward Forces T\u2081,"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["+40-T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082", "+40+T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082", "-40+T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082", "-40-T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for blue block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "+40+T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on blue block?", "options": ["T\u2082 upwards", "T\u2082 downwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "+40+T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082"], "showfc": ["Upward Forces T\u2082,", "Downward Forces "]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of blue block in the y-direction", "options": ["+T\u2082+50=5.0a\u2083", "-T\u2082-50=5.0a\u2083", "-T\u2082+50=5.0a\u2083", "+T\u2082-50=5.0a\u2083"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "+40+T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082"]}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Understanding", "stepNumber": 3, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the dog is moving towards right with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": [0, 5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string is 5 m/s"]}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the dog is moving towards left with speed 5 m/s", "options": [5, -5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": [0, -5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string is -5 m/s"]}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the human is moving towards right with speed 3 m/s", "options": [3, -3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 0], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string is -3 m/s"]}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the human is moving towards left with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 0], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string is 3 m/s"]}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in right direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [5, -5], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"]}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 6, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"]}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards right direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [2, -2, -8, 8], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 7, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is 2m/s"]}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in right direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 8, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"]}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 9, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"]}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards right direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [2, -8, 8, -2], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 10, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is 8m/s"]}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in left direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 11, "threejssubsubstep": [3, -5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"]}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [3, -3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 12, "threejssubsubstep": [3, -5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"]}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards left direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [8, -8, -2, 2], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 13, "threejssubsubstep": [3, -5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is -8m/s"]}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in left direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 14, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, -5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"]}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 15, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, -5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"]}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards left direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-2, -8, 8, 2], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 16, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, -5], "show": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is -2m/s"]}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Equations", "stepNumber": 4, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for pink string:", "options": ["+a\u2081", "-a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "+40+T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082", "+T\u2082-50=5.0a\u2083"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for pink string:", "options": ["+a\u2082", "-a\u2082"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "+40+T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082", "+T\u2082-50=5.0a\u2083"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "+a\u2081-a\u2082=0", "-a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "-a\u2081-a\u2082=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "+40+T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082", "+T\u2082-50=5.0a\u2083"]}, {"question": "What is the number of parts which change length in the red string?", "options": [5, 4, 2, 3], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "+40+T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082", "+T\u2082-50=5.0a\u2083", "+a\u2081-a\u2082=0"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for red string:", "options": ["+a\u2082", "-a\u2082"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "+40+T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082", "+T\u2082-50=5.0a\u2083", "+a\u2081-a\u2082=0"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2082 for red string:", "options": ["+a\u2083", "-a\u2083"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "+40+T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082", "+T\u2082-50=5.0a\u2083", "+a\u2081-a\u2082=0"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for red string?", "options": ["+a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "+a\u2082-a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082-a\u2083=0"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+30-T\u2081=3.0a\u2081", "+40+T\u2081-T\u2082=4.0a\u2082", "+T\u2082-50=5.0a\u2083", "+a\u2081-a\u2082=0"]}]}]